A technician can make a diagnosis
but it costs 15 euros plus VAT.
It has become difficult
to find parts for this.
It's not worth repairing.
Repair will cost 110-120 euros.
Printers cost as low as 39 euros.
I would advise you buy a new printer.
It's best to buy a new one.
We live in a society dominated
by a growth economy
whose logic is not creating because we
need things, but just for the sake of it.
Man decided to shorten a
products lifespan to 1000 hours.
Christmas Eve 1924 was a special day.
In a backroom in Geneve, suit wearing
men met to create a secret plan.
They established the
first worldwide cartel.
Their goal was to control
the production of lightbulbs
and to divide the world
market between them.
The cartel was called Phoebus.
They would change the patents,
control the production
and above all control consumption.
It is better for the companies that
bulbs must be changed more often.
Long lasting lights are an
economic disadvantage.
Phoebus decided to limit the lifespan
of a light bulb to 1000 hours.
In 1925 they appointed a group
called "The 1000 Hour Life Committee",
that would technically reduce the time
an incandescent lamp could burn.
Here we have a cartel document:
One measure was to set up
a stand with many shelves
to which different types of
lightbulbs were connected to
so that the company Osram was able
to register how long they lasted.
Here we have a list of fines from 1929.
It shows how many Swiss
Francs companies had to pay
for example, here when the life
of a bulb was about 1500 hours.
Officially, Phoebus never existed, although
it's tracks have always been there.
The strategy has been to
constantly change names.
They used the name
"The International Energy Cartel" and others.
The point is that this idea
as an institution still exists.
Growth Society's logic is not
only to grow to meet demand
but to grow for the sake of growth;
unbounded growth in production
that is justified through the
boundless growth in consumption.
The three crucial factors are advertising,
planned obsolescence and credit.
Anyone who thinks that infinite
growth is consistent with a finite planet
is either crazy, or an economist.
The problem is that now
we've all become economists.
With this Growth Society we
are sitting in a racing car
that no longer has a driver,
is running at full speed
and will end up crashing
into a wall or driving off a cliff.
I have found the chip called an EEPROM,
which stores a preset number of prints.
When the user reaches this preset
number of prints, the printer locks up.
I bought this DDR-fridge in 1985.
It is 24 years old.
The light bulb is the same age,
I have never changed it. It is 25 years old.
In 1981 when the East Germans
presented the bulb at a fair in Hanover,
our colleagues in the West said,
"You will make yourselves unemployed."
East Germans engineers
replied, "On the contrary."
"By saving resources and not wasting
tungsten we will keep our jobs.""
The transport sector would
pay the actual costs of shipping,
not to mention the fact
that oil is unrenewable,
if the current price was
multiplied by 20 or 30.
'Environment' is generally linked to
saving, reduction, zero waste, etc.
But nature doesn't save anything, for
example when a cherry tree blossoms.
Nature produces no waste,
only nutrients.
Imagine a sofa or a chair
with a fabric like this;
it's decorations are so toxic that it
must be handled as hazardous waste.
Now we select edible materials. You should
be able to have this with your muesli.
In a waste-based society,
products will cause problems.
But if manufactureres use nutrients, the
products can become something new.
A true revolution requires
a cultural change,
a paradigm shift and
a change in mentality.
Anti-Growth is a provocative
slogan that will break
the way of thought that considers infine
growth to be possible and sustainable.
It marks the necessity
to change our logic.
The main message of anti-growth is
to reduce our environmental footprint,
our waste, overproduction
and overconsumption.
By reducing production and
consumption we get more free time
to develop other forms of
wealth that can't be exhausted,
for example friendship
and learning.
If happiness was dependent
on our consumption level,
we should be 100% content.
We consume 26 times more
than in Marx's time.
But all studies show that people
are not 20 times happier.
For happiness is always subjective.
To return to a society of
sustainable development
is not to go back to the
Stone Age, but to the 1960s.
It is far from the Stone Age.
Anti-Growth Society
meets Ghandi's vision:
"The world is big enough to
satisfy everyone's needs,"
"but will always be too small
to satisfy individual greed."